Albin, please.
We'll shoot the
scenes in reverse order...
in the unlikely event that
we stop to build emotionally.
The lyricism, you'd do well to
emulate. Albin, you clear the set.
Roll camera.
And... begin.
Nice pussy.
Meow.
You're very content right now,
aren't you, Ellen?
You live in a nice house.
You wear pretty clothes,
and you're married to a kind man
who's promised to love you forever.
You have no inkling of what lives
at the bottom of the flower box.
No sense of longing.
No notion,
even of death itself.
And...
end, and print it.
Wolf, have we established
pathos?
Perfectly, Herr Doctor.
And in one take.
Very well. Let's get the
film to the lab immediately.
I'll need to see rushes tomorrow
before the train in the morning.
Albin?
Yes, Friedrich. Hurry
and strike your set.
You never hesitate to remind me it's
costing our investors a fortune daily.
Shooting outside the studios
will cost you much more.
But such is the price
of genius.
Thank God, an end
to this artifice!
Nicely done, Greta.
You are developing
in a number of lovely ways.
For a moment, I even thought I saw a
premonition of evil cross your face.
It wouldn't surprise me with all this
spooky shit you've been saying to me.
I told you it's important
for the realistic effect.
But why do we have to
leave Berlin just now...
at the start
of the theatre season?
Albin, has your man
arranged the cars? Yes, two.
Do you have any idea the parts
I've been offered at long last?
The salaries?
Will that be enough?
It has to be. They're the
only cars in the region.
Herr Doctor,
you're ignoring me.
There was a time
when you didn't ignore me.
Greta, why would you possibly want to
act in a play when you can act in a film?
A theatrical audience
gives me life,
while this thing
merely takes it from me.
Greta, Ellen is a woman
who discovers...
the ultimate expression
of love...
in the most exquisite pain
imaginable.
Does that sound familiar?
It's a very
demanding role.
It is the role that will
make you great as an actress.
Consider it a sacrifice
for your art.
Work quickly, ladies and
gentlemen. We have a train to catch.
Hans.
Albin, what did
you give the cat?
- Laudanum.
It's hard to keep the damn
thing docile under the lights.
Why, did it show? It
looked a little pickled.
Not as much as Greta.
Things seem to be
well in hand here.
Friedrich. Friedrich.
Friedrich, we have to
talk about the vampire.
Not now, Albin.
It's nearly dark.
Wrap things up for me
here, will you?
Make sure the imbecile,
Gustav, does not miss the train.
And I'll see you all
in the morning.
But what kind of clothes
should I pack for him?
What kind of makeup?
How tall is he?
Please, tell me, Friedrich.
Does anybody know
where he's running off to?
Perhaps he has a woman.
Or a man.
We cross the border into Czechoslovakia
a few hours into our journey.
Apparently, Herr Doctor has already
filmed some of the exteriors there.
He has?
You didn't know?
No.
Strange.
Well, you can assume we'll be
filming all of Jota's scenes there.
The scenes between
him and the vampire.
I thought Dracula
lived in Transylvania.
Uh-uh, strictly speaking,
this is not Dracula.
The author's widow wouldn't
sell us the rights to the novel.
So, who's playing Count
Dracula? I mean, Orlock.
His name is Schreck.
Max Schreck.
Apparently, he was in the Reinhardt
Company when Murnau was directing.
Schreck. You sure
you have the name right?
- He's a character actor.
- Who told you he was playing the vampire?
- Herr Doctor told me. - I never heard of
Max Schreck in the Reinhardt Company.
Herr Doctor told me he was
with Stanislavsky in Moscow.
Oh, dear. One of
the Russian school then.
As part of his preparation, he
submerges his own personality...
into that of the character
he's playing.
That is why
he is not travelling with us.
Herr Doctor told me he went
to Czechoslovakia weeks ago,
to absorb the flavour
of the place, I suppose.
Herr Doctor
also told me...
that when we get there
and start filming,
Max Schreck will only appear to
us in full makeup and costume,
as the vampire.
Furthermore,
we will only film him...
at night.
And why wasn't I told
about it? I'm the producer.
Well, he told me.
Tell me you're not too
pretty to work for me.
Yes, sir.
I love the cinema.
Friedrich, I just
realized this morning,
our financiers, they don't know
what picture you are making.
The crew don't know
what picture you're making.
The cast don't know
And now, I don't know what picture
you're making. Are you happy?
Albin. I know. Tell them nothing.
There he is.
Gentlemen, I'm Albin Grau, producer
and art director oft his picture.
Is it true Murnau is filming
Stoker's Dracula?
Friedrich Wilhelm Murnau
is Germany's greatest film-maker,
in a class with such masters
as Refice and Eisenstein.
At present, he is
supervising every detail...
of this unique
on-location expedition.
The major part-- who's going
to play? Thank you, gentlemen.
Will you be filming in
Germany? Thank you, gentlemen.
Our battle, our
struggle is to create art.
Our weapon is
the moving picture.
Because we have
the moving picture,
our paintings
will grow and recede.
Our poetry will be shadows
that lengthen and conceal.
Our light will play
across living faces...
that laugh and agonize.
And our music will linger
and finally overwhelm...
because it will have
a context...
as certain as the grave.
We are scientists engaged
in the creation of memory.
But our memory will
neither blur, nor fade.
What is this?
It looks like blood.
Good evening.
Herr Doctor,
we've been expecting you.
Will you see to our baggage?
The wagon train has arrived,
And here's the lead mule.
Well, what a terrible journey that
was. How long have you been here?
- Not long.
- Don't tell me we have a busy schedule tomorrow.
Gustav, no exterior shots at the inn. Some
shots in here, arrival of Hutter's carriage.
Welcome. Welcome.
Friedrich, I'd like to plan
for these night scenes.
When are they
to be filmed?
They will be filmed soon,
Wolf,
but they won't require
much planning.
But I need extra help
to set up the lights.
Surely, you can give me
some notice so I can prepare.
Herr Doctor,
where are the extras?
You're looking at them.
Doctor, these people
cannot act.
They don't need to act.
They need to be.
Wolf?
Herr Müller?
Sorry, Wolfgang.
Allright, Hutter, it's been
a fitful night, but you wake refreshed,
eager to continue your journey
to the castle of the nobleman,
who may very well
make your fortune.
Wait, Gustav.
What is that beside you?
Yes. Pick it up.
It's a book...
about vampires.
Ah! Yes.
Now you remember.
It was put there last night by the superstitious
peasants, the ones who warned you...
not to enter
Orlock's castle.
The ones who warned you not
even to dare to speak his name--
Nosferatu--
the unclean,
the undead.
Lest you invoke
the creature itself.
Very good, Gustav.
Herr Doctor.
Albin?
I am sorry,
Herr Doctor, but--
Albin!
Yes, Friedrich.
Albin, a native has
wandered into my frame.
Kommen sie, Fräulein.
Wolf.
Wolf!
What is the matter
with everyone?
She will not let us go on filming,
unless we replace the crosses.
Am I really being bothered
with this?
Herr Doctor,
I warned you.
You should be more concerned
about these things.
The crosses are not
for decoration.
We will put them back. They
just overwhelm our composition.
Albin, the camera. Yeah, that
light should be sufficient.
We must go. Henrik,
what's the scene number?
Uh, 23.
Quickly.
Yes, Albin, that's fine.
He'll take care of it.
Go in.
Henrik, on either side.
You open the door
when I give you the cue.
Ready?
Are we ready?
Yeah, yeah.
And roll camera.
Iris in.
And... begin.
Gustav, you walk in
very slowly.
Very slowly, yes.
Feel your bag. Make sure
you have your contracts.
You're afraid.
Who was the person
who brought you?
You must go
into the castle.
The castle calls you.
The gates suddenly open.
You must go in.
That's excellent, Gustav.
Go forward.
And... end.
Wolf?
Yeah, it's okay.
I'm in charge
of their construction.
Who built all this?
We have an agreement.
Albin, Albin, I sent some local
workers ahead this morning.
I'm sorry
I didn't explain to you.
Please, there's a generator in the
courtyard, just past the tree on the right.
Get it to work
and replace this camera.
We had an agreement! Yes.
Stay here for a moment.
Wolf, your camera's here. Set it
up as quickly as possible. Yes?
Roll camera.
Gustav, you move forward
very slowly,
heading always
for the tunnel.
This is effect.
Just a dark hole,
that has been unexplored,
untouched...
for long, long time.
And then, one night,
something crawls out.
Hutter...
meet Count Orlock.
Gustav, you must follow him
into the tunnel.
Yes. Going in.
Make your way down.
And...
end.
Wolf?
My God!
Yeah, got it.
Remarkable.
The overture
to our symphony of horrors.
Genius, Hutter, genius.
He is not from
the Reinhardt Company.
Mm. Congratulations,
Gustav.
Yes. I was good,
wasn't I?
I saw his face.
His face.
Where did you find him
really?
In that hole.
Gustav, this was
your finest moment.
Good, Gustav. Gentlemen, let's pack up.
Shooting is completed
for the night.
That's it? We came all
the way for one scene.
I would have driven anywhere at
any time for that look of Gustav's.
I would like to congratulate Herr
Schreck on his extraordinary appearance.
For the remainder of the
shoot, he will be Count Orlock,
to himself
and to all of us.
Just leave the man alone. He
will be completely authentic.
He's not interested in our questions
or our praise or our conversations.
He's chasing an altogether
different ghost.
Friedrich, come quick,
it's Wolf.
Is my room ready?
Yes.
Nosferatu!
Oh, this is too much.
Answer me, Herr Doctor, is this
some stunt to evoke fear in us?
Henrik, stop being so theatrical.
You'll wake the whole house.
Go on up, Wolf,
and have a brandy.
You'll feel better
in the morning.
What's happened?
He's ill, obviously.
Take him upstairs,
and then go outside and help Herr
Grau with the camera equipment.
Bring the cameras
straight to my room,
and prepare for tomorrow.
Albin, we need to
clear the table.
We'll need the inkwell,
the quill and the contracts.
Wolf, I'd like it darker
and smokier.
In which case I thought,
move that lamp to the far side.
And you, spread some dust
on the floor.
Ah! There you are.
It's incredible, no?
I wish you could all
see your faces.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Max Schreck,
who will be portraying
our vampire, Count Orlock.
As you no doubt have heard,
Max's methods are somewhat...
unconventional,
but I am sure...
you will come to respect
his artistry in this matter.
Now. Yes, places,
everybody.
May I have the chair,
please? Quickly.
Count Orlock, you will sit
here at the head of the table.
Please.
Very good.
In this scene, the count is
reading the papers you brought him.
And you are about to make
a considerable amount of money.
No! No makeup!
Forgive me.
Albin, clear the set.
Okay.
Count, you're
reading your documents.
That's it.
It isn't right.
Well, try acting it, for
God's sake. What should it say?
It's meant to be a contract.
A real estate contract.
- I'd like some makeup.
- Well, you don't get any.
Allright. Are we ready
to begin?
Elke, the phonograph.
Ruhe, bitte. Iris in.
And...
concentrate.
Begin.
Allright, Orlock, very good.
You're reading your papers.
Read your papers
very intensely.
After all, how often is it that you
get correspondence from the living?
No, don't look up.
Concentrate on your papers.
Not that you actually care about
the details of the contract.
All you're interested in are all
those juicy throats waiting for you...
the moment
you get to Germany.
Now, Hutter, even though
it may repel you,
creep in, creep in.
Let us see the expectation
on your face.
You are about to make
the biggest sale of your life.
Point out a few details
of the contract. Yes.
Tell him that's-- that's
particularly beneficial to you.
Reach into your bag.
This will seal the deal,
and something falls out.
Count, what is it, on
your left, on the table?
It's a locket.
This is Greta Schroeder.
No, you don't know her. He's
supposed to ask who it is.
Oh.
No. End.
Jesus, Max! Henrik, can
you explain to him...
his motivation?
All right. Count,
think about this.
What is it that inspires...
the most longing in you,
that is most desirable,
and yet, most unattainable?
The light of the sun.
That is the emotion.
Use it.
Nosferatu, you read
your papers. Ruhe, bitte.
Who is this woman?
Ellen, my wife.
She has
a beautiful bosom.
- Jeez!
- Gustav, just snatch it back from him.
Yes, go on. And, vampire,
you sign the papers.
T- Take your quills.
Sign the papers.
Yes, go on.
I understand...
we are going to be neighbours.
Very nice addition,
Count, yes.
And, Hutter, how does
that make you feel?
Yes, snatch back
your papers.
You're happy to be
his neighbour?
And iris out.
End. Excellent.
Excellent.
Give the lip-readers
a thrill.
- Wolf, do you have it?
- Yes, I got it.
- Wolf, have you got it?
- Yes, I said I got it!
Excellent.
Thank you.
Do you think Schreck is allright?
We have left him up at that castle.
He's not in danger.
He's a fine actor, but all this
preparation, it's... very strange.
You think it is strange enough for him
to go so deep inside his character that--
that he forgets he's Max Schreck
altogether? God knows I forgot.
Schreck's peculiarities
are like lovemaking games.
You believe them when they happen,
but they always stop short...
of anybody
being seriously hurt.
"The woods decay.
"The woods decay
and fall.
"The vapours
weep their burthen...
to the ground."
Dinner?
You set
a very mean table.
No rats?
There was a time...
when I fed
from golden chalices.
But now--
Don't look at me
that way!
In my old age,
I feed
the way old men pee.
Sometimes all at once.
Sometimes drop by drop.
I told you...
I feed erratically.
Often, enormously.
Yes, Max, you may
give the locket to Elke.
Now, Gustav, this is a scene
from the previous night.
You have met your host. He has
brought you home to his castle.
He is giving you dinner.
You can start eating.
Very well. Excellent. And, Orlock,
you're merely reading your papers...
and totally ignoring
your guest.
Good.
Wolf, roll camera.
And...
begin.
A thought occurs to you.
Look at your host.
Very good, Gustav.
Do you think...
he might have been the stranger
who drove you to the castle?
You watch.
Is he even human?
How does it feel
to be eating next to him...
knowing that you're spending the
night with him in the castle alone?
You watch him.
Orlock, drop your paper.
Look at Gustav.
Gustav,
keep watching him.
Take your right hand
and reach for the bread knife.
Watch him.
Breathing.
What will happen?
Reach out,
take the loaf of bread...
and cut yourself
a slice.
Yes, slicing.
Slicing.
You're slicing.
Toward you.
Watching him.
Slicing. Slicing.
Watch out.
Slicing.
- Watch your... finger!
- Aah!
Look, Nosferatu, blood!
Blood!
Stop it, Murnau.
I really did cut my hand.
Paul, go and check the generator.
He did that intentionally.
Calm down!
I'll see to the light.
That knife was sharp like a
razor! Gustav, remain in character.
Jesus Christmas!
Get this Scheisskopf off me!
Schreck!
What is the matter
with you?
He's a Stanislavsky lunatic! That
is what is the matter with him!
I have contracted you in secrecy
and at great expense.
You will not damage
this production!
Herr Muller, when will you have
your equipment functioning properly?
I am tired of your
lack of enthusiasm!
I saw you.
Gustav, bring the girls to the car.
I am not happy!
Gustav, move!
Herr Doctor, the man
is barely breathing.
I told you
to fix the generator!
No, leave the equipment
and take the camera.
We are done here for
today, Herr Doctor. Albin!
Help me. Everybody to the automobile.
Herr Doctor, we're leaving.
Schreck.
No. No, he stays.
Albin?
Yes, Friedrich.
Do you think Wolf's assistant
can finish this film?
Paul? No. He hasn't
had enough experience.
What about you?
You're the closest we have
to a photographer.
What are you talking
about? The film ends here.
No, Henrik,
this film will go on.
Henrik, this film cannot survive
even the briefest interruption.
The financiers would take
control. They hate your script.
Actually, it may be
advantageous...
because it makes the crew
very edgy and I like that.
Do you hear what you're saying?
I can drop Wolf at a hospital.
You're out of your fucking
mind. You're a fanatic!
Please, don't behave
like children, Henrik!
I'll get a new photographer and
fly him back here within the week.
Henrik, when you wrote
this scenario,
you had demons of your own
to work out, did you not?
Now I have mine.
Albin,
you're the producer.
Keep this company
together.
How dare you!
How dare you destroy my
photographer! You idiot!
Did I kill... some of
your people, Murnau?
I can't remember.
We have an arrangement!
Don't pretend you mourn,
Herr Doctor. I know you.
Why him, you monster?
Why not the...
script girl?
The script girl...
I'll eat her later.
No, you will not.
Our bargain--
you agreed
not to hurt my people.
Listen to me.
Do you understand?
This requires that
I go back to Berlin...
to find another photographer
and to fly him back here.
And you! You will control
yourself while I am away.
I don't think...
we need the writer any longer.
I don't expect you
to understand this,
and I am loathe
to admit it myself,
but the writer
is necessary.
All my crew
Do you understand?
I don't think the ship
is necessary.
What?
The ship.
My God, what are you
talking about?
I have a dozen scenes
on the ship.
But... I won't sail.
Then I will replace you
with a double!
I will do every scene of yours
You, you will have no close-ups.
None whatsoever.
How dare you speak
to me that way!
I have shots!
I am the director!
Why didn't you
mention this before?
You want to eat the writer?
Be my guest.
That will leave you to explain
how else your character...
is supposed to
get to Bremen.
Yes, I will...
shoot the scenes
at sea around you.
But you will still have to sail
to Helgoland for your death scene.
Or else what?
Or else?
Or else... no Greta.
We shoot her scenes there.
I'll go to Helgoland,
but I won't sail.
Helgoland is an island.
So? So, it can only be reached by sea.
Or air.
And if I agree to fly you in,
you will leave my people alone.
Or else what?
Don't think
I can't harm you.
Tell me how
you would harm me,
when even I don't know
how I could harm myself.
But thy strong hours
indignant worked their wills...
and beat me down,
and marred and wasted me.
And though they
could not end me,
left me maimed to dwell...
in presence of immortal youth.
Immortal age beside
the immortal youth...
and all I was in ashes.
Albin, what is the most wondrous
thing you have ever seen?
Eh, I saw ectoplasm once.
Ectoplasm?
What is ectoplasm?
It's the mystical substance
of ghosts.
I saw a spiritualist pull
it out of his mouth in Italy.
What did it look like?
Seaweed.
Is that what we look like when
we die? I hope not.
What was for you...
the most wondrous thing
you ever saw?
I once saw
Greta Schroeder naked.
No.
Yes.
That beats ectoplasm.
Jesus, Max.
You scared me
to death.
How long have
you been listening?
We've been looking all
over the place for your coffin.
Maybe it isn't
his resting place.
Didn't we have something
to say to him?
Max? The great
Friedrich Wilhelm Murnau...
went to Berlin to find
a new photographer.
Wolf is probably dead. So you
can take your funny ears off.
Alb, please.
The man is an artist.
Ask him some
vampire questions.
When did you become a vampire?
I can't recall.
Where were you born--
were you born?
I can't remember.
It's not funny anymore.
Come on, Count Dracula wouldn't
say he couldn't remember.
I read that book.
Murnau gave it to me.
Well, now this is a golden
opportunity. Speaking as a vampire,
what do you make of the
book's technical merits?
It made me sad.
Why sad?
Because Dracula
had no servants.
I think you missed the point
of the book, Count Orlock.
Dracula hasn't had servants
in 400 years,
and then a man
comes to his ancestral home,
and he must convince him
that he--
that he is like the man.
He has to feed him,
when he himself hasn't
eaten food in centuries.
Can he even remember
how to buy bread?
How to select
cheese and wine?
And then he remembers
the rest of it.
How to prepare a meal,
how to make a bed.
He remembers
his first glory,
his armies,
his retainers,
and what
he is reduced to.
The loneliest part
of the book comes...
when the man accidentally...
sees Dracula
setting his table.
But if you're so lonely,
why don't you
make more vampires?
I can't.
I'm too old.
Although,
I seem to remember
I was never able to.
Then how did you
become a vampire?
- It was woman.
- Now we're getting somewhere.
Schreck,
the German theatre...
needs you.
We were together in the
night, and then she left me.
At first, I had a painting
of her in wood,
then I had a relief
of her in marble,
and then,
I had a picture of her...
in my mind.
But now, I no longer
even have that.
What was I saying?
This Schnapps they make
in these parts.
I haven't tasted it in--
Take it easy there,
old boy.
Henrik, what an actor.
Yeah.
Dedication.
Herr Schreck.
Herr Doctor!
You wanted reality,
Herr Doctor, here it is.
Well, I'm not a doctor, but I
have dabbled in pharmaceuticals.
You're the new cameraman?
Ja.
Paul is setting up
to shoot it now. Good.
Art can never move as fast
as life, huh? Ah, sure it can.
So, what's the lens?
It's 35 millimetres, sir.
Not my ideal weapon of choice,
but I suppose it will do.
Are you loaded?
Yes, sir.
Good, so am I. Move the camera
ten centimetres to the right,
and I'll contrive a possible
two-shot, but wait for my signal.
Did you get the shot?
Yes, sir.
And the gate is clean?
The gate's clean, sir.
I hadn't time to properly
prepare the shot.
What I should have done was
film the thing in slow motion.
It would have been
incredibly moving.
What's that, sir,
slow motion?
Well, I run the film
through the camera too fast,
then when it's projected
at normal speed,
things appear to be
unnaturally slow.
Gives everything
a kind of resonance.
It's a shame you won't have
the chance to demonstrate...
your more esoteric skills
on my production.
I'm Albin Grau,
the producer.
"And at dawn, Hutter tried to
fathom the horrors of his nights."
Excellent.
Fritz, roll camera.
Iris in.
Begin.
And end.
Excellent, Gustav.
Extraordinary discipline
in the face of ridicule.
Fritz?
Yes, well, that's his
performance style.
Yes, I'd like to move in
for another angle...
on the crypt,
please, quickly.
Mark the shot
with some chalk.
Well, I am exhausted now,
and I'm hungry as well.
You will get a nice hot meal in Wismar,
right after we're done with the ship.
And... end.
Have you ever
considered acting?
No, really. You have
a very interesting face.
Why can't Herr Doctor film in
a studio like everybody else?
Henry, could you take
my dog for me? Choo Choo.
Oh, and thank you.
Foo Foo.
Wismar--
Is there anything here...
that even vaguely
resembles a cabaret?
I mean I'm suffering for
my art, Albin, believe me.
Melodrama. I mean
what's going on here, anyway?
You know, Friedrich tells me
to lock my door at night,
and Gustav says
everybody's vanishing.
Oh, and you can imagine what
they're saying in Berlin.
Hello, Greta.
Hello.
You look vaguely familiar.
Where did we meet?
Morocco.
Ah, yes, of course.
You brought me treats.
Ja, ja.
What was your
name again? It's--
Shh, shh, shh--
Eh, Fritzie. Ja, ja. Fritzie.
Yes, Fritzie.
Fritzie. Would you care
to join us for a drink?
No, no, no. We have to pre light the set.
What-- What set? What the
hell are you talking about?
We need you to see the
sets with us tonight, Fritzie.
Well, give me back
my dogs then.
Here.
Thank you, yes.
Left all alone as usual.
Come here, Foo Foo.
She's here,
isn't she?
The glorious child.
No. I want to see her now.
No.
I won't act for you again
until you bring her to me.
You are destroying
everything.
My people have to trust me
for you to get what you want.
You and I are not
so different.
Greta is in
your last scene.
That is when
you can have her.
After my death scene?
Yes.
Don't expect realism there,
Murnau. What do you mean?
Don't cheat me, mortal.
You will stay away
from her.
from my crew.
I will finish
my picture!
This is hardly
your picture any longer.
You are ready?
Yes, I'm ready.
Mind your head.
This is it.
He's in here?
Yeah.
You sure?
Well, that answers
that question.
How did you find this place?
I followed Murnau here.
Henrik, I think you're in the
wrong part of the building.
There's probably
a sadistic brothel upstairs.
What's wrong?
It's all right.
Everyone back to bed.
Greta, Greta,
what is it?
Greta,
Greta, Greta.
What's happened, Greta?
Please.
It's morphine.
Morphine?
Photography
and pharmaceuticals...
by Fritzie, that's just what I
need. Friedrich knows all about it.
What do you mean
he knows about it?
He knows all about it.
She's fine. Don't worry.
Get some sleep.
Are you all right there?
This set is not ready.
Can we get any
natural light in here?
Fritz, the set is not ready, and you're
talking about natural light. Please.
What's the matter
with you, Albin?
You seem a little
anxious lately.
You don't understand.
I'm ruined.
I'll never make
another picture again.
My reputation, gone, and you talk
about natural light. Please, Fritz.
Don't worry. It's the
same on every picture.
Not on my picture.
Friedrich, open up!
It's me, Albin.
Friedrich,
let us in!
Oh, Jesus.
What is it?
It's laudanum.
That's what it is.
There is no
Max Schreck.
If he's not Max Schreck,
who is he?
I don't know.
Well, where did
you find him?
In a book.
When I was a student,
a series of paintings...
portraying a long line
of despotic kings...
rumoured to be vampires,
living in Slovakia
for hundreds of years.
I had forgotten
all about that,
until she gave me
the other book.
What other book, Friedrich? Dracula.
Then I went to scout
the locations,
and there he was,
living in
an old monastery.
What kind of bargain
did you make with him?
That he would play the part
of an actor...
playing the part
of a vampire.
Why?
What did you offer him
in return?
Everlasting life.
And Greta.
Greta?
How could you do this,
Friedrich?
I did it for science.
To preserve it
for posterity.
Friedrich.
Friedrich!
He's gone.
Come on.
What are we going to
do? The call is for 2:00.
Albin, listen to me.
There's no way
off this island.
What about the airplane I saw?
No, no. I already checked it.
The fuel tanks are empty.
Car?
Nope.
We're going to have to film
Schreck's scene tonight.
You know I don't like
these late shoots, Friedrich.
Where is everybody?
Why don't I have
an assistant?
Greta...
did you put on this makeup
with a broom?
Stop fussing, Albin. You look beautiful.
Can I have a cigarette?
Sure.
Where's my script?
Henrik?
He's indisposed. What's
the matter with him?
Greta, don't ask so many
questions. We're busy.
Thank you, darling.
Why does everybody
look so depressing?
Hey!
Who died?
Jesus,
look at you.
Friedrich?
- Herr Doctor?
- Yes, Greta, what is it?
"Yes, what is it?"
What's the shot?
What are we
doing here?
Can you stand for me?
Look at you.
Yes, very well.
Now, let us
take her robe.
Albin, please.
And she'll need
her wooden stake.
Also, Greta,
you will be here,
lying on the bed.
Yes.
Good.
Now, in this scene,
you make the ultimate
sacrifice for love, yes?
Yes.
You will seduce
the count,
and with
your wooden stake,
just before you die,
you will
dispatch him, yes?
Clear? Very good.
In other words,
all you have to do...
is, as they say, relax,
and the vampire
will do all the work.
You had me leave rehearsals
in Berlin just to do that?
Hey!
Watch it, handsome.
And for your lean-in,
please, Herr Schreck.
Thank you.
And, Albin,
her shoes, please?
- We must go aboard.
- Friedrich?
Yes? I don't wish to
question your authority,
but are you sure you know
what you are doing?
Yes, exactly.
Roll camera.
And Fritz, ready?
Higher.
And... iris in.
What's happened?
I saw--
He-- He casts no--
He casts no reflection.
Calm down, Greta.
I see it.
No, look at him!
Look at him!
Look!
Please, help me. Help
me, please, Friedrich.
We'll give you something to
calm you-- No, don't do that.
Oh, Albin, look at him, please. Please.
No! No!
I don't understand what--
It is the role that will
make you great as an actress.
Consider it a sacrifice
for your art.
That's better,
now we can work in peace.
I want her now.
No.
I need a shot of you
clutching your heart first.
My death scene?
Yes.
You must do that for me.
Very well.
Roll camera and begin.
Yes, Count.
You kneel down,
you'll have your head
on her shoulder,
but you're not feeding,
Count.
No, you're not
drinking her blood now...
because you have been
drinking her blood all night.
In fact,
you can barely move.
You are intoxicated...
with-- with blood
and desire.
Greta, can you hear me?
Yes?
Flutter your eyelids.
Yes, now, Greta,
you start to awaken.
Find your stick.
Yes, where is it?
Now, Count, as she raises
the stake, what do you see?
Yes, yes. A wooden stake,
exactly. You look at her.
Betrayed.
Yes, you turn,
you rise, you look around.
The sun is coming.
You grab your heart
in anguish.
Yes, and you start
to die.
Yes, you start to die,
alone... in anguish. Die, you--
you fucking rat bastard,
vampire pig,
Schweinehund, shit!
Yes! Die alone!
Let the weight
of the centuries bend you.
And... end!
Fritz?
Ja, got it.
That's enough, Murnau.
Hey!
I want her now.
Herr Schreck, bitte.
Go to hell, Murnau.
Begin!
Very good, yes.
Now slowly, let's move
the camera around.
Friedrich, he cut the chain.
We're trapped!
So, you would...
break our bargain.
01:20:29,735 but I can still kill you.
I can break your necks,
drink your blood,
and I can--
You tried to trick me!
It's daybreak, is it?
So what?
All I need...
is to sleep
in darkness.
I'll stay here
until dusk.
And then only I...
will walk out alive.
Idiot.
Frankly, Count, I find
this composition unworkable.
Could you return
to your original mark, please?
If it's not in frame,
it doesn't exist.
Then finally,
you must turn...
to meet the sun.
The death of centuries,
moon chaser, blasphemer,
monkey vase of prehistory...
finally to Earth,
and finally born.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
You take the sun.
Albin, could you quickly
collect...
the wooden stake and return
it to its rightful place?
It is necessary
for the final frame,
to remind us of the
inadequacy of our plans.
Our contingencies,
every missed train,
the failed picnics,
every lie to a child.
Softly, please.
Our work
is nearly complete.
Our very own painting
on our very own cave wall.
Time will no longer be
a dark spot on our lungs.
They will no longer
be able to say,
"You would had to
of been there."
Because the fact is,
Albin, we were.
Is there one among you who might
wear the mantle of camera assistant?
Could I possibly
impose on you...
to collect the slate
at my feet,
and provide me
with an end board?
Turn it.
Thank you.
I think we have it.